Finding Aid for the Edouard Roditi Papers LSC.0644
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Printed material by or about Édouard Roditi.
  - Terrier by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 104)
    [Paris?]: Galerie Saphir, n.d.
    Brochure for an exhibition by Jean-Michel Terrier.
  - LE TOMBEAU DU SOLEIL by Philippe Laburthe-Tolra [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 104)
    vol. 36 (April / May / June 1988), p. 60.
    With "Defense et illustration du galimatias," p. 55-58, and reviews, p. 63-64, signed M. d'A. and E.R.
  - Writers from French North Africa by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 104)
    Series Title: JANA
    vol. 1, no. 12 (April 1955), p. 50-54.
    Unsigned article.
  - Writers in French North Africa - Part I by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 104)
    vol. 1, no. 11 (March 1955), p. 36-37.
  - Contes moraux by Spingarn, Lawrence. (Box 104)
    vol 24 (June 1985), p. 40-41.
    Translation by Edouard Roditi. With "Entretien avec Marino Marini," p. 49-60, and "[Note]," p. 63-64, signed B.N. [Bernard Nissim].
  - Galleria Umberto by Spingarn, Lawrence. (Box 104)
    vol. 23 (March 1985), p. 38-39.
    Translated by Nissim Bernard, pseudonym of Edouard Roditi. With "La recuperation des oublies de Pont- Aven," p. 56-58, and a review p. 68-70.
  - FAHRELNISSA ZEID by Zeid, Fahrelnissa. (Box 104)
    Amman: Royal National Jordanian Institute Fahrelnissa Zeid of Fine Arts, 1984.
    Excerpt from Edouard Roditi's DIALOGUES ON ART, p. 156-158.
  - Nos lecteurs nous ecrivent by Bowles, Paul. (Box 105)
    (February 9, 1980), p. 2, 4.
    Part 3 of a 3 part series by Edouard Roditi and Paul Bowles.
  - An open letter by Bowles, Paul. (Box 105)
    (January 12, 1980), p. 1, 4, 8.
    Part 1 of a 3 part series by Edouard Roditi and Paul Bowles.
  - L Association Avatar et humanity international by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 105)
    (February 2, 1980), p. 3, 5.
    Part 2 of a 3 part series by Edouard Roditi and Paul Bowles.
  - Fascino del quiproquo by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 105)
    Series Title: LA FIERA LETTERARIA
    Complete issue.
  - Jugendstil ist wieder Mode by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 105)
    Series Title: MODERNSLEBEN
    (October 13, 1961), p. 38.
  - Lectures, poetry readings by Edouard Roditi - announcements - ephemera by Roditi, Edouard, collector. (Box 105)
    Box 33 is an oversize flat box.
  - Takal: Selected works - Part I Drawings - Part II Images a fair mourir les sirenes des nostalgies by Takal. (Box 105)
    New York: International University Press [c1954].
    English translation by Edouard Roditi, appended separately. Photocopy.
  - Amerikanische Lyrik. (Box 106)
    Series Title: U.S. INFORMATION CENTER WEEKLY BULLETIN
    no. 5 (May 24, 1946), p. [1].
    Re ER's lecture. Clipping. Removed from scrapbook.
  - Art exhibition. (Box 106)
    (February 20, 1932), p. [ ].
    Mention of ER as a guest at an art exhibition, "Peintres res rares, tres curieuses," at the Randolph Hotel. Clipping. Removed from scrapbook.
  - Berlinprivat [newspaper column]. (Box 106)
    Series Title: BERLINER MORGENPOST
    (June 7, 1975), p. 8.
    Mention of ER's 65th birthday. Clipping.
  - France - culture [radio-television schedule]. (Box 106)
    Series Title: LE MONDE
    (August 18-19, 1974), p. 12.
    Announcement of interview with Edouard Roditi. Clipping.
  - Geklaerte Turbulenz. (Box 106)
    Series Title: DER KURIER
    no. 106 (May 10, 1948), p. 3?
    Mention of ER. Clipping. Removed from scrapbook.
  - HORIZON [review]. (Box 106)
    Series Title: INVENTARIO
    no. 1 (1946), p. 151-152.
  - An important event. (Box 106)
    Mention of ER at a party given by Peggy Ashcroft and Eric Alport. Clipping. Removed from scrapbook.
  - Un jeune poete. (Box 106)
    Series Title: CAHIERS JUIF
    Review of ER's POEMS FOR F. Clipping. Removed from scrapbook.
  - Limits to 'The voice'. (Box 106)
    Series Title: KANSAS CITY STAR
    (April 9, 1950), p. [ ].
    Interview with ER regarding the Voice of America. Clipping.
  - Modern amerikanische Lyrik. (Box 106)
    Series Title: FRAENKISCHER TAG
    Re ER's lecture, "Moderne amerikanische Lyrik". Clipping. Removed from scrapbook.
  - OSCAR WILDE by Edouard Roditi [book review]. (Box 106)
    Series Title: NEWSWEEK
    (January 5, 1948), p. 34.
    Clipping. Removed from scrapbook.
  - Poetic history. (Box 106)
    Series Title: NEW YORK SUN
    (March 13, 1944), p. [ ].
    Re an article by ER in POETRY regarding the "contemporary approach to diction, plot and character". Clipping removed scrapbook.
  - Speaking of books by Adams, J. Donald. (Box 106)
    (September 26, 1943), p. [ ].
    Re ER's reply to Adams' article on the nature of poetry. Clipping removed from scrapbook.
  - Les huit jours de Paris by Andreas, Edouard, pseud. (Box 106)
    Series Title: MARIANNE
    (April 18, 1934), p. 9.
    Edouard Andreas is one of Roditi's pseudonyms. Clipping.
  - Wilde as a maker of literature by Baker, Carlos. (Box 106)
    Series Title: [no title given]
    (n.d.).
    Review of ER's OSCAR WILDE. Clipping. Removed from scrapbook.
  - Festival interpreter uses more than words by Carmody, Jay. (Box 106)
    Series Title: THE EVENING STAR
    (July 17, 1957), p. [ ].
    Regarding ER at the Berlin Film Festival. Clipping.
  - THE STIFFEST OF THE CORPSE by Codrescu, Andrei. (Box 106)
    San Francisco: City Lights Books [1989].
    "Kantian considerations on cats" by Edouard Roditi, p. 232.
  - Death camps known about earlier [Letter to the editor] by Donaghue, Terence, pseud. (Box 106)
    Series Title: POLITICS
    (September 1945), p. 286.
    Terence Donaghue is one of ER's pseudonyms. Clipping. Removed from scrapbook.
  - Cultivate your garden by Enzensberger, Hans Magnus. (Box 106)
    (July 1956), p. 250-251.
    Translated by Edouard Roditi. With "The elect and the damned" by Alexander Koval, translated by Edouard Roditi, on page 252. Clipping.
  - Faith without conversion by Goodman, Paul. (Box 106)
    vol. 60, no. 5 (August 1942), p. 282-285.
    Review of PRISON WITHIN PRISON: THREE ELEGIES ON HEBREW THEMES by Edouard Roditi. Clipping removed from scrapbook.
  - Edouard Roditi: Restoring the Symbolists, among other things by Kanter, Larry. (Box 106)
    Series Title: OBERLIN REVIEW
    (January 25, 1974), p. 3.
    Profile of ER as Artist-in-residence. Clipping.
  - Oscar Wilde: Art without pain by Kaplan, Harry. (Box 106)
  - Ein Vergessener - Edouard Roditi ueber Joachim Karsch by Kinkel, Hans. (Box 106)
    Series Title: FRANKFURTER ALLGEMEINE ZEITUNG
    no. 266 (November 14, 1968), p. [ ].
    Re ""Bildende Kunst in Berlin". Clipping.
  - The elect and the damned by Koval, Alexander. (Box 106)
    (July 1956), p. 252.
    Translated by Edouard Roditi. With "Cultivate your garden" by Hans Magnus Enzensberger, p. 250-251. Clipping.
  - A la mode [newspaper column] by Martin, Nora. (Box 106)
    Proof sheets.
  - The man from Rhodes by Mazonson, Diane. (Box 106)
    Series Title: THE PEMBROKE RECORD
    (February 19, 1968), p. 3.
    Profile of ER, visiting professor, Brown University. Clipping.
  - Klaus Mann ueber Gide by Montijo, E. (Box 106)
    Series Title: DER TAGESSPIEGEL
    (May 9, 1948), p. [ ].
    Mention of Roditi. Clipping. Removed from scrapbook.
  - Dada und Blumen by Ohff, Heinz. (Box 106)
    no. 5821 (November 1, 1964), p. [ ].
    Mention of ER's interview with her in MONAT and his DIALOGUES ON ART. Clipping.
  - And inhumanities .. by Palmer, Christine. (Box 106)
    Series Title: [DAILY MAROON]
    Clipping removed from scrapbook.
  - Edouard Roditi interview by Pearson, Gregory. (Box 106)
    Series Title: EXPATRIATE REVIEW
    no. 4 (Winter / Spring 1973/74), p. 23-31.
  - Oscar Wilde, Dichter und Dandy by Edouard Roditi [book review] by Pfeiffer-Belt, Erich. (Box 106)
    Series Title: DIE NEUE ZEITUNG
    (December 22, 1974).
    For the column "Buecherchronik". Removed from scrapbook.
  - Expose by Power, F. (Box 106)
    (1939?), p. [ ].
    Re ER and a campus controversy, University of Chicago. Clipping removed from scrapbook.
  - A mascara inglesa de Fernando Pessoa by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    Series Title: LUSCADA
    (December 1954), p. 89-93.
  - L age de la nuit [translation by Ivan Goll] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    Series Title: LA VOIX DE FRANCE
    (August 1-15, 1942), p. [ ].
  - Amerykanski poeta kontemplacyjny by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    Series Title: KULTURA
    (n.d.), p. [135]-141.
  - Art forgery [ENCYCLOPEDIA BRITANNICA, 1967] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    Series Title: ENCYCLOPEDIA BRITANNICA
    (1967), p. 513-515.
  - Die Aufnahme der Bundesrepublik in internationale Organisationen by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    Series Title: AKTION
    (August 1951), p. 13-17.
  - Avatar by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    (19832), p. [ ].
  - THE AXIS GRAND STRATEGY by Ladislas Farago [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    (August 1942), p. 58.
  - La ballade de Sankt Pauli by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    Series Title: LES CAHIERS MENSUELS
    3rd series, no. 6 (June 1931), p. [ ].
  - THE BATTLE IS THE PAY-OFF by Captain Ralph Ingersoll [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    (December 1943), p. 61.
  - A capital without a country by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    Series Title: THE REPORTER
    (January 31, 195), p. 36-38.
  - Comrade Gide by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    (July 17, 1936), p. 109.
    Review of LES NOUVELLES NOURRITURES by Andre Gide. Clipping removed from scrapbook.
  - Czasopisma kulturalne Niemiec by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    (September 1950), p. [102]-116.
  - Czysciec i piekto polityki by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    (n.d.), p. 198-200.
  - LA DENONCIATION by Jacques Mazeau [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    (Autumn 1956), p. [ ].
  - Editorial by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    Series Title: ULENSPIEGEL
    vol. 3, no. 2 (February 2, 1948), p. [ ].
    Translation by Alexander Koval. Clipping. Removed from scrapbook.
  - Editorial by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    (Autumn 1946), p. 11.
  - Les expositions by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    Series Title: EVIDENCES
    no. 57 (n.d.), p. 47-[49].
    Review of Monticelli, Schwarz-Abrys and Lutka Pink. Clipping.
  - LE GENIE ET LA DEESSE by Aldous Huxley, translation by Jules Castier [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    no. 3 (1956), p. [ ].
  - Gluckel de Hameln: Priere du soir by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    no. 59 (n.d.), p. [11].
  - THE GREAT OFFENSIVE by Max Werner by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    Series Title: TOMORROW (August 1943), p. 59.
  - Habakkuk by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    Series Title: COMPASS
    (Summer 1939), p. 34-35.
  - Les heritiers de Cezanne by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    no. 62 (Jan. / Feb. 1957), p. [48-49].
  - UN HOMME POUR UN AUTRE by Alain Bosquet [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
  - Jean-Jacques Rousseau agrees with Miss Sitwell by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
  - Josef Herman by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    Series Title: LES BEAUX ARTS
    no. 760 (Feb. 15, 1957), p. [ ].
  - LEGENDES AMERICAINES ET AUTRES by Alexander Woollcott, translated by Denise Van Moppes [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
  - Leon Blum by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    (July 2, 1937), p. [ ].
    Review of L'EXPERIENCE BLUM and LEON BLUM: FROM POET TO PREMIERE by Richard L. Stokes. Clipping removed from scrapbook.
  - Letter to the editor by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    Series Title: JOURNAL OF AESTHETICS AND ART CRITICISM
    vol. 6, no. 1 (September 1947), p. 85-86.
  - A literary letter about East Germany by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    (December 7, 1952), p. [ ].
  - A literary letter from Portugal by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    (November 18, 1951), p. [ ].
  - A literary report on East Germany by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    (February 11, 1951), p. [ ].
  - Litterature et peinture by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    Series Title: PENSEE FRANCAISE
    no. 11 (September 1957), p. [12]-18.
  - Londres [art review column] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    Series Title: SOCIETE DES AMATEUR ET COLLECTIONNEURS D'ART
    (1931), P. [ ].
    Reviews of exhibitions by Jacob Epstein (Leicester Galleries) and young English painters (Atelier Barnard). Clippings. Removed from scrapbook.
  - MAIDEN VOYAGE by Denton Welch [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    (n.d.), p. 72.
    Proof sheet. Removed from scrapbook.
  - Manhattan novellettes by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    vol. 12, no. 68 (August 1948), p. [82]-83.
  - Marcus Behmer by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    Series Title: THE STUDIO
    (June 1957), p. 182-183.
  - Mediterranee by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    Series Title: CAHIERS JUIFS
    (July 1936), p. 529-530.
    Review of LE BALAI DE SORCIERE by Armand Lunel. Clipping removed from scrapbook.
  - Monolog mit Miro by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    Series Title: FORUM
    (February 1960), p. 76-80.
  - Moslems speak and write French by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    (no. 90 (October 1955), p. 182-185.
  - The new reality by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    vol. 10, no. 49 (June 1929), p. 295-300.
  - OVERCOMING ANTI-SEMITISM by Solomon Andhill Fineherg [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    (October 1943), p. 61.
  - Para las mujeres de los involuntarios by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    Series Title: THE CLIPPER
    (January 1941), p. 30.
  - Paralisi intellettuale by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    (January 4, 1953), p. [ ].
  - Paris 1986: Eight formerly Soviet painters from Paris by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
  - Le philosophe dans les neiges by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    (April 10, 1936), p. [ ].
  - Poem by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    vol. 11, no. 56 (November 1931), p. [ ].
    Poem begins "To love is not only to touch the loved hands". Clipping. Removed from scrapbook.
  - Poem [untitled] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    (n.d.), p. 17.
    Poem begins "lions of the sands soft fawning manes". Clipping. Removed from scrapbook.
  - Poem for L by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    no. 21 (December 20, 1946), p. 14.
  - Quelques peintres - Steinhardt au Stedelijk by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    no. 64 (April / May 1957), p. [47]-48.
  - RAPHAEL, JE VOULAIS TE DIRE ... by Clarisse Nicoidski [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    (Spring 1986), p. [ ].
  - Rash modern poets by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    (March 18, 1944), p. [ ].
    ER's published letter to the editor. With carbon copy of his typescript, March 13, 1944). Clipping and letter removed from scrapbook.
  - Le reve de Cassandre by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    Series Title: ACCORDS
    (August 1947), p. 13-16.
  - ROBERT MUSIL OU L'ALTERNATIVE ROMANESQUE by Jean-Pierre Cometti [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    (Winter 1987), p. [ ].
  - Romantisme et realisme Americains by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    (n.d.), p. 42-47.
    With introduction by O. Montreuil. Clipping. Removed from scrapbook.
  - SOURCES OF ART NOUVEAU par Stephan Tschudi Madsen [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    no. 770 (April 16, 1957), p. [ ].
  - Surrealisten unter sich by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    (December 1963), p. 621-[incomplete].
  - TEACHER IN AMERICA by Jacques Barzun [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
  - TIGERS ON THE TENTH DAY by Zakaria Tamer, translation by Denys Johnson-Davies [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
  - TOUT L'ETE by Jean Blot [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
  - Trafalgar Square by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    Series Title: THE CRITERION
    Proof sheets. Removed from scrapbook.
  - Turkish painting in Paris and Edinburgh by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    Series Title: ART NEWS AND REVIEW
    (August 17, 1957), p. [5].
  - Two poems by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    (Summer 1945), p. 5.
    "Aubade" and "The acrobats". Clipping.
  - Two poems by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    vol. 41, no. 4 (January 1933), p. 194-195.
    Untitled poems beginning "No hour can be darker ... " and "Elder and hemlock bathe ... " Clipping.
  - La voix eteinte de la Poesie Allemande by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    Series Title: LE JOURNAL DES POETES
    no. 5 (May 1947), p. [ ].
  - La voix eteinte de la Poesie Allemande by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    no. 4 (April 1947), p. 9.
  - War and spring by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    Series Title: NEW HORIZONS
    vol. 2, no. 4 (July / August 1940), p. 11.
  - THE WRONG ANGELS by Stanley Moss [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    (n.d.), p. 318-384.
  - Die X. internationale Konferenez fuer Medizin der Arbeit by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    (January 1952), p. 35-37.
  - THE ZOHAR IN MOSLEM AND CHRISTIAN SPAIN by Dr. Ariel Bension [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 106)
    new series (December 1932), p. 225-226.
  - RADIO GOES TO WAR by Charles J. Rolo [book review] by Roditi,Edouard. (Box 106)
    (May 1942), p. 53.
  - Roldan [essay by Edouard Roditi] by Roldan. (Box 106)
    Series Title: GALERIE 3 + 2
    Paris (November / December 1966).
    Exhibition brochure with essay by Roditi.
  - Edouard Roditi as literary mediator by Rosenfeld, Sidney. (Box 106)
  - POEMS FOR F by Edouard Roditi [book review] by Sayers, Michael. (Box 106)
  - Die oeffentliche Einsamkeit by Schneider, Konrad. (Box 106)
    (January 21, 1948).
    Review of OSCAR WILDE: Dandy und Dichter by Edouard Roditi. Removed from scrapbook. 3 copies.
  - Sweetness and light [newspaper column] by Schoen, Lillian. (Box 106)
    ((1939), P. [ ].
    With contribution "Humanities" by Edouard Roditi and "Inhumanities" by Christine Palmer, University of Chicago. Clipping removed from scrapbook.
    See also "Expose" by F. Power, poem re Roditi and above column.
  - Images a faire mourir les sirenes de nostalgie by Takal. (Box 106)
    New York: International University Press, n.d.
    Translated into English by Edouard Roditi. Xerox copy.
  - Book reviews - AS A MAN GROWS OLDER by Italo Svevo, introduction by Edouard Roditi. (Box 107)
    Clippings.
  - Book reviews - CONTES HIEROGLYPHIQUES ET AUTRES BIZARRERIES by Horace Walpole, tr. Edouard Roditi. (Box 107)
  - Book reviews - DE L'HOMOSEXUALITE by Edouard Roditi. (Box 107)
  - Book reviews - DIALOGE UEBER KUNST by Edouard Roditi. (Box 107)
  - Book reviews - DIALOGUES ON ART by Edouard Roditi. (Box 107)
    Clippings
  - Book reviews - EMPEROR OF MIDNIGHT by Edouard Roditi. (Box 107)
  - Book reviews - JEWISH ART FROM THE BEGINNING TO THE PRESENT, edited by Cecil Roth. (Box 107)
    Edouard Roditi was one of the contributors. Clipping.
  - Book reviews - LES PLUS BELLES LETTRES DE DELACROIX PRESENTEES by Edouard Roditi. (Box 107)
  - Book reviews - MAGELLAN OF THE PACIFIC by Edouard Roditi. (Box 107)
  - Book reviews - MEIN LIEBLINGSMORD by Ambrose Bierce, afterword by Edouard Roditi. (Box 107)
  - Book reviews - MEMED MY HAWK by Yashar Kemal, translated by Edouard Roditi by. (Box 107)
  - Book reviews - NEW DIRECTIONS 24, edited by James Laughlin. (Box 107)
    Series Title: PUBLISHERS' WEEKLY
    (January 14, 1972), p. 65.
    With ER's "The Vampires of Istanbul" especially recommended. Xerox copy.
  - Book reviews - OSCAR WILDE by Edouard Roditi. (Box 107)
  - Book reviews - OSCAR WILDE by Edouard Roditi [New Directions, 1986]. (Box 107)
  - Book reviews - POEMS, 1928-1948 by Edouard Roditi. (Box 107)
  - Book reviews - PRISON WITHIN PRISON by Edouard Roditi. (Box 107)
  - Book reviews - PROPOS SUR L'ART by Edouard Roditi [Corti edition]. (Box 107)
  - Book reviews - THE DELIGHTS OF TURKEY by Edouard Roditi. (Box 107)
  - Book reviews - THE PILLAR OF SALT by Albert Memmi, translated by Edouard Roditi by. (Box 107)
  - Book reviews - THRICE CHOSEN by Edouard Roditi. (Box 107)
  - Book reviews - YOUNG CHERRY TREES SECURED ...HARES by Andre Breton, translated by Edouard RoditI. (Box 107)
  - Distinguished visitors. (Box 107)
    Oxford newspaper. The column "La Gazette" mentions ER, Evelyn Waugh, and A.P. Herbert at a weekend gathering. Clipping.
  - Die Krankheit der Deutschen Galerien. (Box 107)
    Series Title: FEUILLETON
    (February 15, 1963), p. 7.
    Subtitle: Ein ketzerischer Vortrag Edouard Roditi, Paris. Clipping.
  - Malen die Deutschen franzoesisch. (Box 107)
    (February 15, 1963), p. 9.
    Subtitle: Provozierende Thesen von Edouard Roditi in der Stuttgarter Akademie. Clipping.
  - Noticiario - [Roditi visit]. (Box 107)
    Series Title: REPUBLICA DAS LETRAS E DAS ARTES
    (February 28, 19690, p. 2.
    Re ER's visit. Page 1 is autographed by Portuguese poet Carlos Faria. With ER's holograph note.
  - Ambadas [essay by Edouard Roditi] by Ambadas. (Box 107)
    Gallery Chemould: Bombay [1968].
  - Taninmis, sanat elestiricisi Edouard Roditi Istanbulda by Andak, Selmi. (Box 107)
    Series Title: BAYRAM GAZETESI
    (18 Nisan 1959), p. [ ].
  - Fedor Ganz - introduction by Edouard Roditi by Ganz, Fedor. (Box 107)
    [Paris]: Francoise Besnard, n.d.
    Exhibition invitation.
  - L' authenticite marocaine [introduction by Edouard Roditi] by Hamri. (Box 107)
    Exhibition catalogue.
  - Von fast unbregrenzter Freiheit und einer Anthologie by Hermlin, Stephan. (Box 107)
    Series Title: TAEGLICHE RUNDSCHAU
    (December 15, 1948), p. 17.
    Re literary controversy with ER. Clipping.
  - Understanding McLuhan - Letter to the editor by Higgins, Dick. (Box 107)
    (July 17, 1967), p. 27.
    Re ER's article on McLuhan in the June 19 issue. Clipping.
  - List literata o Niemczech Wschodnich by Rodit, Edouard. (Box 107)
    no. 5/67 (1953), p. 109-111.
  - A 'Estatua de Sal' de Alfred Memmi by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 107)
    (May 5, 1955), p. 21.
  - Ahmed Cherkaoui pas mort by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 107)
    no. 544 (June 8, 1971), p.3-5.
    For the column "Forum". Clipping.
  - L' art Musulman au Musee de l'Orangerie (Paris) by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 107)
    no. 555 (July 20, 1971), p. 8-9.
    For the column "Expositions". Clipping.
  - Artisant des pays francophones ... Antonio Bandeira by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 107)
    no. 580 (February 19, 1972), p. [ ].
  - Arts ... A New York ... A Paris by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 107)
    For the column "Arts". Clipping.
  - Au Musee Galliera ... A l'UNESCO by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 107)
    no. 567 (November 20, 1971), p. 64-65.
  - Benkemoun ... Neuschul ... Marwan by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 107)
    no. 560 (September 28, 1971), p. 66-67.
  - Benkemoun et l'ecole Marocaine de la peinture moderne by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 107)
    Series Title: MAROC TOURISME
    (n.d.), p. [56]-57.
  - Bernard Buffet - Der Maler szieschen Melancholie und Manierismus by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 107)
    Series Title: FILM UND FRAU
    (n.d.), p. 10-13, 44-45.
    Translation by Katharina E. Russell. Clipping.
  - Bertold Brecht - letter to the editor of DER MONAT by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 107)
    no. 98 (n.d.), p. 85-88.
  - Book-buying in East Berlin by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 107)
    Series Title: THE NEW REPUBLIC
    (October 17, 1955), p. 23.
  - Breyten et Fradan by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 107)
    (March 11, 1972), p. 66-67.
  - 'Le cachalot blanc, c'est moi!' by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 107)
    Series Title: PSYCHE
    no. 98 (December 1954), p.[675]-680.
    Re Herman Melville and homosexualite. Clipping.
  - Chagalls ungdomsaar by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 107)
    Series Title: POLITIKEN
    (September 9, 1959), p. [ ].
  - Comment enrichir les langues africaines by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 107)
    no. 508 (September 29, 1970), p. 53-54.
    Part of the column "Monde". Clipping.
  - Entretien avec Wotruba by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 107)
    Series Title: PREUVES ?
    (n.d.), p. 69-72.
  - Europe 1907, at the Stadelijk Museum, Amsterdam by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 107)
    (vol. 9, no. 18 (September 28, 1957), p. [ ].
  - Expositions ... A gravers les galeries parisiennes by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 107)
    no. 551 (July 27, 1971), p. 8-9.
  - Fquih Regragui ... Abdelkader Smihi ... Abdellatif Abdi by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 107)